Inventory of the Luis Kutner papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- World Habeas Corpus World Conference
  - Correspondence
    - Tony Weitzel, 1964 (Box-folder 26: 14)
    - Hubert L. Will, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 26: 15)
    - Robert K. Woetzel, 1968 (Box-folder 26: 16)
  - Research Materials, 1967 (Box-folder 26: 17)
- World Center for Human Rights
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box-folder 26: 18)
    Fundraising
  - Miscellany, 1968 (Box-folder 26: 19)
- World Federalists, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 26: 20)
- World Fellowship of Religions
  - Correspondence, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 26: 21)
  - Mailing list, 1968 (Box-folder 26: 22)
- Miscellany, 1971-1976 and undated (Box-folder 26: 23-24)
- World Institute Council, 1968 (Box-folder 27: 1)
- World Law Fund, 1968 (Box-folder 27: 2)
- World Ombudsman Association--Letters and statement, 1968 (Box-folder 27: 3-4)
- World Telethon for World Freedom Centers, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 27: 5-6)
- World without War Council, 1977 (Box-folder 27: 7-8)
  Letters and miscellany
- World without War Education Program, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 27: 9)
- World Anti-Communist League/China chapter, 1968 (Box-folder 27: 10)
  Clippings, correspondence, press release, printed matter, and miscellany
- World Union International Center, 1965-1974 (Box-folder 27: 11-12)
- Correspondence--Isaac Wolfson, Jr., 1962-1971 (Box-folder 27: 13)
  Includes clippings and printed matter
- Clippings and printed matter relating to Africa and Israel, 1962-1965 (Box-folder 27: 14)
- Center for International Advocacy, 1977 and undated (Box-folder 28: 1)
  Notes, printed matter, and miscellany
- Clippings, journals, and printed matter relating to anti-communism, China, human rights, genocide, and U.S. foreign policy, 1966-1978 (Box-folder 28: 2-5)
- Untitled writing by Luis Kutner about human rights, 1978 (Box-folder 28: 6)
- World federalists, 1972 and undated (Box-folder 29: 1)
  Articles, clippings, newsletter, and printed matter
- Printed matter relating to extradition, hijacking, Israeli foreign policy, Japan, and Middle East, 1964-1967 (Box-folder 29: 2)
- Council of Europe, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 29: 3-5)
  Charter, program, and reports
- Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 29: 6)
  - "World Habeas Corpus for International Man: A Credo for International Due Process of Law,", 1959
  - "World Habeas Corpus and International Extradition,", 1964
- Human rights, 1972-1975 (Box-folder 29: 7)
  Check list, letter, minutes of meetings, and statement
- Correspondence (Box 30)
  - Julius Stukman, 1969-1974 (Box-folder 30: 1)
  - Roger Fisher, 1967 (Box-folder 30: 2)
  - Joseph S. Clark, 1967 (Box-folder 30: 3)
  - George Dewey, 1967 (Box-folder 30: 4)
    Includes 1 photographic print depicting Dewey, undated
  - Lord Russell, 1967 (Box-folder 30: 5)
  - Ralph J. Bunche, 1967 (Box-folder 30: 6)
  - Edward Lawson, 1967 (Box-folder 30: 7)
  - Lee Edwards, 1967 (Box-folder 30: 8-9)
  - William W. Bishop, Jr., 1967 (Box-folder 30: 10)
  - World Wide Press, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 30: 11)
  - Miscellany, 1967 (Box-folder 30: 12-13)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to amnesty, human rights, genocide, situation in Angola, Tshombe affair, and torture and oppression, 1967-1978 (Box-folder 30: 14-24)
- Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 30: 25-26)
- Isaac Wolfson (Box 31)
  - Correspondence and drafts of speech, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1954-1966 (Box-folder 31: 2-3)
  - Miscellany, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 31: 4)
- Miscellaneous correspondence, 1964-1965 and undated (Box-folder 31: 5-6)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to the U.S. Bill of Rights and Constitution, fiduciary principles, human rights, and miscellany, 1949-1978 and undated (Box-folder 31: 7-10)
- Miscellany, 1969 and undated (Box-folder 31: 11-12)
  Draft of world habeas proprietatem treaty statute, notes, organizational chart, and petition
- Printed matter, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 32: 1)
  Informations Congolaises
- World Habeas Corpus: A symposium
  - Correspondence and publishing agreement, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 32: 2)
  - Egon Schwelb, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 32: 3)
- Writings by others, 1957-1979 (Box-folder 32: 4)
- Notes relating to a case, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 33: 1)
- Writings by others, 1954-1965 (Box-folder 33: 2-3)
- Crime victims
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1965-1976 (Box-folder 33: 4)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 33: 5)
  - Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 33: 6)
- Psychic powers, 1973-1978 (Box-folder 33: 7)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to atomic energy and world democracy, charitable trusts and organizations, estate and gift taxes, estate planning, and foundation investments, 1939-1967 (Box-folder 34: 1-3)
- Manuscript by Hardin B. Jones, undated (Box-folder 34: 4)
  Includes 3 photographic prints depicting an unidentified individual, undated
- National Society: Sons of the American Revolution--Petitions filed with the United States Congress, undated (Box-folder 35: 1)
- Corporate advocacy, 1970-1976 and undated (Box-folder 35: 2-5)
  Correspondence, clippings, message, and printed matter
- Clippings and printed matter relating to freedom of speech, issue of privacy, order in college campuses, and tax cuts, 1969-1974 (Box-folder 35: 6-7)
- Miscellany, 1970-1974 and undated (Box-folder 35: 8)
- Cambodia (Box 36)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1965-1975 (Box-folder 36: 1-2)
  - Correspondence (including with Norodom Sihanouk), 1963-1973 (Box-folder 36: 3)
  - Messages, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 36: 4)
- Ethiopia, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 36: 5)
- Cambodia, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 37: 1)
  Clippings and correspondence with Norodom Sihanouk
- Brazil, 1970-1977 (Box-folder 37: 2)
- Ghana
  - Memoranda, statement, and telegram, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 37: 3)
  - Correspondence, 1968 (Box-folder 37: 4)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1963-1968 (Box-folder 37: 5-6)
  - Prisoners' file, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 37: 7)
  - Students Association of the Americas, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 37: 8)
- Chad, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 37: 9)
  Clippings, letters, printed matter, and miscellany
- Chile
  - Correspondence
    - Herrn W. Dosnett Lynas, III, 1974 (Box-folder 37: 10)
    - G. G. Grant, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 37: 11)
    - Miscellany, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 37: 12)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1968-1977 (Box-folder 37: 13-14)
  - Miscellany, 1974 (Box-folder 37: 15)
- Czechoslovakia, 1968 (Box-folder 37: 16)
- Cambodia, 1971-1974 and undated (Box-folder 38: 1-2)
  Announcement, bulletin, declaration, and messages (including to Kurt Waldheim, United Nations Secretary General)
- Brazil
  - Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 38: 3)
  - Virgilio Luix Donnici, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 38: 4)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 38: 5)
  - Miscellany, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 38: 6)
- Correspondence (Box 39)
  - Quincy Wright, 1960-1967 (Box-folder 39: 1)
  - B. A. Wortley, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 39: 2)
  - Sidney R. Yates, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 39: 3)
  - Samuel Young, 1976 (Box-folder 39: 4)
  - Joni Zweig, 1975 (Box-folder 39: 5)
  - Miscellany, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 39: 6)
- Southern Africa, 1976-1978 (Box-folder 39: 7)
  Clippings and printed matter relating to U.S. policy and human rights
- Angola
  - Correspondence
    - Robert Brown, 1975-1977 (Box-folder 39: 8-9)
    - Ved P. Nanda, 1968 (Box-folder 39: 10)
  - Clippings and printed matter relating to prisoners of war and mercenary convention, 1976 (Box-folder 39: 11-13)
- Writing by Luis Kutner--"International Due Process for Prisoners of War: The Need for a Special Tribunal of World Habeas Corpus,", undated (Box-folder 39: 14)
- Miscellany, 1953-1976 (Box-folder 39: 15)
  Note, report, and U.S. Department of Defense documentation relating to political prisoners
- European Court of Human Rights/Luis Kutner, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 40: 1)
- Correspondence
  - Abe Fortas, 1964-1969 (Box-folder 40: 2)
  - Alfredo J. Gamez, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 40: 3)
  - Ann Gillen, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 40: 4)
  - Aaron Gold, 1975 (Box-folder 40: 5)
  - Malvina H. Guggenheim, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 40: 6)
  - Erwin N. Griswold, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 40: 7)
  - Peggy Guggenheim, 1970 (Box-folder 40: 8)
  - "G" miscellaneous, 1972 (Box-folder 40: 9)
  - Mirza Gholam Hafiz, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 40: 10)
  - Maxwell Ham, 1964-1972 (Box-folder 40: 11)
  - Learned Hand, 1955 (Box-folder 40: 12)
  - Phillip Harman--Committee for a Free Panama, 1979 (Box-folder 40: 13)
  - Gideon Hausner, 1968 (Box-folder 40: 14)
  - "H" miscellaneous, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 40: 15)
  - Isaac Wolfson, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 40: 16-18)
- Ghana, 1968 (Box-folder 40: 19)
  Correspondence with Akufo-Addo
- Hawaii, 1968 (Box-folder 40: 20)
  Correspondence and related materials
- Correspondence (Box 41)
  - John Connally, 1976-1980 (Box-folder 41: 1)
  - Jerry Conway, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 41: 2)
  - Bernard Cornfeld, 1970 (Box-folder 41: 3)
  - Jacques Cousteau, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 41: 4)
  - Gardner Cowles, Jr., 1956-1958 (Box-folder 41: 5)
  - Alan Cranston, 1969-1978 (Box-folder 41: 6)
  - Current Magazine, 1965 (Box-folder 41: 7)
  - Sol A. Dann, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 41: 8)
  - David Is-Haq, 1972-1978 (Box-folder 41: 9-10)
  - Lord Denning, 1965 (Box-folder 41: 11)
  - Thomas E. Dewey, 1957-1963 (Box-folder 41: 12)
  - Everett M. Dirksen, 1964 (Box-folder 41: 13)
  - Jim Dolan, 1976 (Box-folder 41: 14)
  - Martin Domke, 1961-1964 (Box-folder 41: 15)
  - William Randolph Douglas, 1974 (Box-folder 41: 16)
  - Sharman Douglas, 1960 (Box-folder 41: 17)
  - Donald C. Dowling, 1959-1963 (Box-folder 41: 18)
  - Thomas A. Doyle, 1966 (Box-folder 41: 19)
  - K. Howard Drake, 1961 (Box-folder 41: 20)
  - Andrzej Drzemczewski, 1972 (Box-folder 41: 21)
  - Alan Edelson, 1975-1978 (Box-folder 41: 22)
  - Edilbert Razafindralambo, 1974 (Box-folder 41: 23)
  - Alona E. Evans, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 41: 24)
  - David Evans, 1979 (Box-folder 41: 25)
  - Frank J. Filippi, 1970 (Box-folder 41: 26)
  - Bernard Frank, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 41: 27)
  - Felix Frankfurter, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 41: 28)
  - John H. E. Fried, 1972 (Box-folder 41: 29)
  - Council for the Study of Mankind, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 41: 30)
  - Albert Blaustein, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 41: 31)
  - Miscellaneous
    - D, 1965-1974 (Box-folder 41: 32)
    - E, 1969 (Box-folder 41: 33)
    - F, 1969-1974 (Box-folder 41: 34)
    - Alan Cranston and others, 1971-1977 (Box-folder 41: 35)
      Current resolution for a surviving world
- Miscellany, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 41: 36-37)
- Correspondence (Box 42)
  - William F. Cahill, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 42: 1)
  - Mary Ellen Caldwell, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 42: 2)
  - Alice Cantacuzene--Lupoaie, 1972 (Box-folder 42: 3)
  - Max Chopnick, 1961-1965 (Box-folder 42: 4)
  - Winston Churchill, 1959 (Box-folder 42: 5)
  - Mark Clark, 1954-1957 (Box-folder 42: 6)
  - American Committee of One Million for Individual Freedom, 1972 (Box-folder 42: 7)
  - Committee on Habeas Proprietatem, 1974 (Box-folder 42: 8)
  - Frank F. Teruggi, 1976 (Box-folder 42: 9)
  - University of Southern California--Dorothy W. Nelson, 1968 (Box-folder 42: 10)
  - Nicholas Unkovic, 1962 (Box-folder 42: 11)
  - Karel Vasak, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 42: 12)
  - Kurt Waldheim, 1973 (Box-folder 42: 13)
  - Theodore Waller, 1959-1977 (Box-folder 42: 14-15)
  - Eloi Langoul--Cameron Republic, 1965 (Box-folder 42: 16)
  - Canadian Bar Association, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 42: 17)
  - Rene Cassin, 1970 (Box-folder 42: 18)
  - N. C. Chatterjee, 1962 (Box-folder 42: 19)
  - Chicago Daily News, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 42: 20)
  - Miscellany
    - C, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 42: 21)
    - U, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 42: 22)
    - W, 1965-1973 (Box-folder 42: 23)
- China, 1962-1973 (Box-folder 42: 24-25)
  Correspondence, clippings about habeas corpus in relation to Hong Kong, and press release
- Miscellany, 1966-1976 (Box-folder 42: 26-27)
- Correspondence (Box 43)
  - Mario Biaggi, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 43: 1)
  - Manual Ramon Ruiz Tejada, 1973 (Box-folder 43: 2)
  - Tran Tam, 1965-1974 (Box-folder 43: 3-5)
    Includes 1 photographic print possibly depicting Tran Tam
  - Justin G. Turner, 1967 (Box-folder 43: 6)
  - Augustin Navarro Vasquez--Instituto de Investigaciones Sociales Y Economicas, A. C., 1971 (Box-folder 43: 7)
  - Lester Velie-- Reader's Digest, 1967 (Box-folder 43: 8)
  - Earl Warren, 1973 (Box-folder 43: 9)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to Ireland, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 43: 10-11)
- Miscellany, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 43: 12-14)
  Includes World Day celebrations and information on American Society of International Law
- Correspondence (Box 44)
  - Earl J. Thomas, 1975 (Box-folder 44: 1)
  - Raymond L. Thurston, 1976 (Box-folder 44: 2)
  - Jan L. Tucker--Florida International University, 1979 (Box-folder 44: 3)
- World Habeas Corpus--Correspondence
  - Tran Tam--World Habeas Corpus, 1973-1975 (Box-folder 44: 4-5)
  - DePaul University
    - Guest lecture, 1968 (Box-folder 44: 6)
    - Law Review, 1963 (Box-folder 44: 7)
    - Moot court, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 44: 8)
  - Detroit Law Journal, 1959-1965 (Box-folder 44: 9)
  - Duke University, 1967 (Box-folder 44: 10)
  - University of Chicago Law Review, 1958-1963 (Box-folder 44: 11)
  - Harvard Law School, 1959-1965 (Box-folder 44: 12)
  - University of Miami Law Review, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 44: 13)
  - New York University Law Review, 1967 (Box-folder 44: 14)
  - Northwestern University Law Review, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 44: 15)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 1967 (Box-folder 44: 16)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 44: 17)
  - Purdue University, 1965-1966 (Box-folder 44: 18)
  - Villanova Law Review, 1963-1967 (Box-folder 44: 19)
  - Virginia Law Review, 1967 (Box-folder 44: 20)
  - Yale Law Journal, 1967 (Box-folder 44: 21)
  - Miscellany, 1957-1969 (Box-folder 44: 22-23)
- Correspondence (Box 45)
  - Albert Blaustein, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 45: 1-3)
  - Don Manuel Ramon Ruiz Tejada, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 45: 4)
  - State Bar of Texas, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 45: 5)
  - Tran Tam, 1965-1972 (Box-folder 45: 6-7)
  - Arthur G. Tillman, Mrs., 1959-1963 (Box-folder 45: 8)
  - Time Magazine, 1964 (Box-folder 45: 9)
  - Khalil Toame, 1968 (Box-folder 45: 10)
  - Walter Trohan, 1967 (Box-folder 45: 11)
  - Otto Triffterer, 1973 (Box-folder 45: 12)
  - Miscellany, 1959, 1976-1977, and undated (Box-folder 45: 13-14)
- Miscellany, 1962 and undated (Box-folder 45: 15)
- Correspondence (Box 46)
  - Roger Baldwin, 1957-1971 and undated (Box-folder 46: 1-2)
  - Romeo Barros, 1975 (Box-folder 46: 3)
  - David L. Bazelon, 1960-1966 (Box-folder 46: 4)
  - John V. Beamer, 1952-1962 (Box-folder 46: 5)
    Includes 1 photographic print depicting Beamer
  - Maximo B. Bello, 1968 (Box-folder 46: 6)
  - Cesar Bengzon, 1965 (Box-folder 46: 7)
  - R. C. Benitez, 1968-1974 (Box-folder 46: 8-10)
  - Francçois Bernard and Stephen P. Marks, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 46: 11)
  - Richard Bilder, 1974 (Box-folder 46: 12)
  - Hugo L. Black, 1960 (Box-folder 46: 13)
  - Albert P. Blaustein, 1976-1980 and undated (Box-folder 46: 14)
  - Baron William von Blomberg, 1979 (Box-folder 46: 15)
  - Yehuda Blum, 1974-1975 (Box-folder 46: 16)
  - Luis Maria Boffi Boggero, 1966 (Box-folder 46: 17)
  - Willy Brandt, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 46: 18)
  - William J. Brennan, Jr., 1962-1967 (Box-folder 46: 19)
  - Alexander D. Brooks, 1962-1963 (Box-folder 46: 20)
  - Edmund G. Brown, 1969-1973 (Box-folder 46: 21)
  - Joseph Bukera, 1974 (Box-folder 46: 22)
  - Mary I. Bunting, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 46: 23)
  - H. Burchard, 1964 (Box-folder 46: 24)
  - "B" miscellaneous, 1967-1974 (Box-folder 46: 25)
  - S. O. Adebo, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 47: 1)
  - Aldine Publishing Company, 1966 (Box-folder 47: 2)
  - Arturo A. Alafriz, 1966 (Box-folder 47: 3)
  - John Alexander-Sinclair, 1963-1972 (Box-folder 47: 4-5)
  - American Bar Association, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 47: 6-10)
  - Amnesty International, 1962-1967 (Box-folder 47: 11)
  - Philip Werner Amram, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 47: 12)
  - Anti-Slavery Society, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 47: 13)
  - Arye Arazi, 1970-1974 (Box-folder 47: 14)
  - Marianne Arbib, 1976 (Box-folder 47: 15)
  - Richard Arens, 1978 (Box-folder 47: 16)
  - Thurman Arnold, 1955-1968 (Box-folder 47: 17)
  - Lou Ashe, 1973 (Box-folder 47: 18)
  - Harry S. Ashmore, 1976-1979 (Box-folder 47: 19)
  - Association Internationale de Droit Penal (AIDP), 1968 and undated (Box-folder 47: 20)
  - Nestor C. Aybar, 1975 (Box-folder 47: 21)
  - Paul C. Davis--Advance Studies Group, 1968 (Box-folder 47: 22)
  - Mark Weinberg, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 47: 23)
  - Miscellany--Save Our Battered Babies, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 47: 24)
- Miscellany, 1969 (Box-folder 47: 25)
- Organization of American States (OAS) (Box 48)
  - Clippings, notes, and printed matter, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 48: 1)
  - Paraguay, 1971-1976 (Box-folder 47: 2-3)
    Clippings, letter, and printed matter
  - Miscellany, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 48: 4-5)
- Pakistan--Zulfikar Ali Bhutto, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 48: 6-7)
  Articles, bulletins, clippings, correspondence, newsletter, and printed matter
- Miscellaneous correspondence--"A" and "W", 1969-1974 (Box-folder 48: 8)
- American Friends of Anti-Bolshevik Bloc of Nations, Inc.--Anathole W. Bederly, 1976 (Box-folder 49: 1)
- Captive nations--Miscellany
  - Bangladesh and Pakistan, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 49: 2-4)
  - Ireland, 1972-1976 and undated (Box-folder 49: 5-10)
  - Paraguay, 1976 and undated (Box-folder 49: 11)
  - Poland, 1970-1977 (Box-folder 49: 12)
- Correspondence (Box 50)
  - Luke P. Carroll, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 50: 1)
  - Ashe Lincoln, 1972-1977 (Box-folder 50: 2)
  - Anthony Marreco, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 50: 3)
  - Everett McKinley Dirksen, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 50: 4)
  - Josef Cardinal Mindszenty, 1949-1972 and undated (Box-folder 50: 5-7)
  - Edith N. Rogers, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 50: 8)
  - Eleanor Roosevelt, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 50: 9)
- Luis Kutner, 1952 and undated (Box-folder 50: 10-11)
  Petition on behalf of William N. Oatis
- Northern Ireland radio broadcast--WBBM editorial, 1972 and undated (Box-folder 50: 12)
- Transcript of diaries of Harold W. Rigney and petition on his behalf, 1949-1955 (Box-folder 50: 13-14)
- Clippings and printed matter relating to human rights and sovereignty, 1951-1975 and undated (Box-folder 50: 15-16)
- China, 1955 (Box-folder 51: 1)
- Northern Ireland, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 51: 2)
- Uganda, 1972-1980 (Box-folder 51: 3)
- Clippings, printed matter, and miscellany
  - Congressional Record, 1953 (Box-folder 51: 4)
  - Human Rights, 1953-1978 (Box-folder 51: 5)
  - World Union and World Citizens Party, 1977 (Box-folder 51: 6)
  - American Society of International Law, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 51: 7)
  - United Nations, 1952-1978 (Box-folder 51: 8)
  - Miscellany, 1953-1979 (Box-folder 51: 9)
- Sierra Leone, undated (Box-folder 52: 1)
  Clipping and note
- Uganda
  - Death threats, undated (Box-folder 52: 2-3)
  - International League for Human Rights, 1977 (Box-folder 52: 4)
  - Clippings and printed matter, 1976-1978 and undated (Box-folder 52: 5)
- William N. Oatis, 1952 (Box-folder 52: 6-9)
  Clippings, correspondence, notes, and petition
- Gray Panthers, undated (Box-folder 52: 10)
- Clippings and printed matter, 1944-1978 (Box-folder 52: 11-14)
  Law journal articles about air pollution, ecoside, energy, environment, recognition of states, and the Gray Panthers, 1944-1978
- Miscellany, undated (Box-folder 52: 15)
- Uganda (Box 53)
  - World Association of World Federalists, 1977 and undated (Box-folder 53: 1-2)
  - Miscellany, 1977-1978 (Box-folder 53: 3-4)
- Amnesty International, 1978 (Box-folder 53: 5)
  Clipping, letters, and report on human rights violations in Uganda
- Environment and pollution
  - State of Illinois, undated (Box-folder 53: 6-7)
  - Lake Michigan Federation, 1974-1976 (Box-folder 53: 8)
  - Writings by others, 1976-1977 (Box-folder 53: 9)
  - Miscellany, 1972-1976 (Box-folder 53: 10-12)
- Articles about Luis Kutner, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 54: 1)
- Correspondence
  - Michael A. Bilandic, 1977 (Box-folder 54: 2)
  - Arthur J. Goldberg, 1967 (Box-folder 54: 3)
  - Harvard University Law School, 1957 (Box-folder 54: 4)
  - Charles A. Rhyne, 1978-1979 (Box-folder 54: 5)
  - Carl F. Salans, 1967 (Box-folder 54: 6)
  - Gustavo Salgado, 1970-1971 and undated (Box-folder 54: 7)
- Writings by Luis Kutner
  - "International Criminal Law" (contributing author), 1969 (Box-folder 54: 8)
  - "World Habeas Corpus"--Book jacket, undated (Box-folder 54: 9)
  - "Statute of the World Court of Human Rights,", undated (Box-folder 54: 10)
  - "World Habeas Corpus, Human Rights and World Community" and "To Make Freedom Real,", undated (Box-folder 54: 11)
- Writings by others, 1950-1969 and undated (Box-folder 54: 12-15)
- World Habeas Corpus, 1964-1970 and undated (Box-folder 54: 16)
  Brochure, printed matter, and miscellany
- World Court of Human Rights, undated (Box-folder 54: 17)
  Announcement
- Miscellany, 1958-1976 (Box-folder 54: 18-19)
- World Future Society--Newsletter, The Futurist, 1968-1970 and undated (Box-folder 55: 1-2)
- World Habeas Proprietatem
  - Miscellany, 1964-1966 (Box-folder 55: 3)
  - World Garanty Investment Organization, 1965 (Box-folder 55: 4)
- United Nations writ
  - Correspondence, 1954 (Box-folder 55: 5)
  - News release, printed matter, publicity, and miscellany, 1954 (Box-folder 55: 6)
    Includes an article by Luis Kutner, "Proposal for a United Nations Writ of Habeas Corpus and an International Court of Human Rights," undated
- Church of God, undated (Box-folder 55: 7)
- World Peace through Law Center
  - Correspondence
    - 1974-1976 and undated (Box-folder 55: 8)
    - 1964-1965 (Box-folder 56: 1-2)
- Human rights
  - Miscellany, 1943-1976 (Box-folder 56: 3-6)
  - Writings by Luis Kutner (Box-folder 56: 7)
    - "World Habeas Corpus: The Difference between Civilization and Tyranny,", undated
    - "World Habeas Corpus and International Extradition, 1964
    - "World Habeas Corpus and the Rule of Law, 1969
- Clippings and printed matter relating to disarmament and world peace, environment, human rights, and miscellany, 1962-1972 (Box-folder 57: 1-5)
- American Society of International Law, 1971 (Box-folder 57: 6)
  Conference and related materials
- World University, 1969-1970 and undated (Box-folder 57: 7)
  Articles, letters, and printed matter
- Miscellany, 1971 (Box-folder 57: 8)
- World Habeas Corpus, 1957-1972 (Box-folder 58: 1-2)
  Articles, clippings, printed matter, and speeches by others
- World Peace through Law Center, 1959-1973 (Box-folder 58: 3-4)
  Clippings, correspondence, printed matter, and related materials
- World Habeas Corpus, 1951-1967 (Box-folder 59: 1-2)
- Human rights, 1965-1976 and undated (Box-folder 59: 3-6)
- Writings by Luis Kutner
  - "Comments on the establishment of a Committee for Latino Public Justice,", undated (Box-folder 59: 7)
  - "International Law Basis of International Due Process of Law,", undated
- Gerhard Miller, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 59: 8)
  Comments on practical possibilities of international habeas corpus movement, and letters
- Andrew Lee, 1967 (Box-folder 59: 9)
  Articles, clippings, letters, and miscellany
- Articles about Luis Kutner, 1972 (Box-folder 60: 1)
- Correspondence and miscellany, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 60: 2)
- Writings by Luis Kutner
  - "The Role of the Special Powers Act in the Protestant Ascendancy of Northern Ireland,", undated (Box-folder 60: 3)
  - Report--Mission to Northern Ireland, 1972 (Box-folder 60: 4)
- India, 1976 (Box-folder 60: 5)
- Taiwan and Northern Ireland, 1965-1976 (Box-folder 60: 6-7)
  Miscellaneous materials relating to human rights and with reference to the United Nations
- World Policy Planning Institute (Box 61)
  - American Institute of Aeronautics and Astronautics, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 61: 1)